<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Uprooted on Uprooted: The Faces of the Venezuelan Crisis</title>
    <link>https://uprooted.unc.edu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Uprooted on Uprooted: The Faces of the Venezuelan Crisis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright School of Media and Journalism</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 21:34:53 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://uprooted.unc.edu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Hopeful Voice</title>
      <link>https://uprooted.unc.edu/a-hopeful-voice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 21:34:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uprooted.unc.edu/a-hopeful-voice/</guid>
      <description>By 4 p.m., Irelys Rojas begins to fear the end of the day.
It’s raining, and the restaurants she performs in are empty. At 5, she sits down at a café to count how much she’s made for the day.
It’s $24,000 Colombian pesos, or about USD $8.
She needed USD $33 to afford rent, a bus ride and the single meal she eats per day. The rest — about USD $20 — she planned to send to her parents and the three sons she left behind in Margarita Island off the coast of Venezuela.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brothers on the Pitch</title>
      <link>https://uprooted.unc.edu/brothers-on-the-pitch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 21:35:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uprooted.unc.edu/brothers-on-the-pitch/</guid>
      <description>“¡Hay que terminar!”
“You have to finish!” Soccer players with Adidas-striped shoulders shout from the sidelines as their teammates complete a four-on-four drill. The next wave of defenders enters the field, causing black turf beads to fly through the air. One player, wearing all white, save for his neon yellow cleats, slides toward the ball, tripping the offensive player looking for an open man.
“¡Sigue jugando!”
“Keep playing!” The ball travels like a current between the defender’s feet, as he dribbles it to safety.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Home</title>
      <link>https://uprooted.unc.edu/a-new-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 21:34:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uprooted.unc.edu/a-new-home/</guid>
      <description>After leaving behind their home country, where most Venezuelan immigrants spent their entire lives, families are forced to start over. Migrants find new places to live wherever they can around the city. Some live night to night in different inquilinatos, while others live in rented apartments and others still find one-room homes to buy. In most cases there is not enough room for families to sleep comfortably.
Andrea Blanco Rondón holds her children (from left) Lilian, Elisa and Andres on their bed in a one room home in the Santo Domingo comuna in Medellín.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greater than Death</title>
      <link>https://uprooted.unc.edu/greater-than-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 21:35:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uprooted.unc.edu/greater-than-death/</guid>
      <description>Marbis Judith Verenzuela, 53, knew she had to go back. Her oldest daughter, Jorlis, was still in Venezuela. So last December, she traveled back from Colombia to save her family.
Jorlis, 29, had surgery to remove a brain tumor in 2012, but still experiences side effects from the operation. She had been suffering from convulsions for 30 days because she couldn’t get the medicine she needed to control her seizures, and had been staying in a hospital in Maracay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Family, Together</title>
      <link>https://uprooted.unc.edu/a-family-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 21:34:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uprooted.unc.edu/a-family-together/</guid>
      <description>After traveling hundreds of miles on foot, a group of five Venezuelans, who together call themselves a family, arrived in Medellín on February 27th. Before leaving their homes, they all held different, honest jobs including food service and hair care but were all laid off over the course of the last year due to a crumbling economy. Now in Colombia, the family works 15 hour days asking for money in exchange for small candies on the street in order to make enough money to afford food and a tiny room to sleep in each night.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cost of Dreams</title>
      <link>https://uprooted.unc.edu/cost-of-dreams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 21:35:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uprooted.unc.edu/cost-of-dreams/</guid>
      <description>It took four arepas to fill 6-year-old Jeham Carlos’ stomach. But he decided to get by on just two because his parents struggled to keep enough food in their house back home in Venezuela.
He never told his parents he was still hungry. He didn&amp;rsquo;t want them to worry. They had enough worries already. Three years later, his mother, Alejandrina, cries as she hears her son talk about this tender sacrifice for the first time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making it in Medellín</title>
      <link>https://uprooted.unc.edu/making-it-in-medellin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 21:34:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uprooted.unc.edu/making-it-in-medellin/</guid>
      <description>Creating a new life in a new country is no easy feat, especially for the Venezuelan people. Many of these immigrants in Colombia strike an uphill, as their journeys have faced many obstacles in their search to restart or preserve their way of life. This dream of success isn’t impossible, however. These Venezuelans have done just that; whether it be living life without debt for the first time or preserving a family business, these Venezuelans have found a way to survive for their families.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Mother&#39;s Sacrifice</title>
      <link>https://uprooted.unc.edu/a-mothers-sacrifice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 21:36:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uprooted.unc.edu/a-mothers-sacrifice/</guid>
      <description>CONTENT WARNING: This article contains information and depictions of sexual assault, child sexual abuse and sexual content that may be triggering for some. Car honks and bicycle bells erupt in the ears of locals and tourists passing through Plaza Botero.
A light breeze flows through the skyscraping palm trees of the plaza. It’s cool enough to alleviate the sun’s heat but not cool enough to give one goosebumps.
But in the land of eternal spring, the weather is often unpredictable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Journey</title>
      <link>https://uprooted.unc.edu/what-they-carry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 21:34:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uprooted.unc.edu/what-they-carry/</guid>
      <description>As resources dwindle, violence erupts, and corruption becomes rampant, Venezuelans cope with the reality of leaving their home. They are forced to leave nearly everything behind in search of a safer life. However, some items are held near and dear as families and individuals escape the turmoil that has overridden their country. Venezuelans hold these items close to their heart while they hope for the day that their country will return to peace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home About</title>
      <link>https://uprooted.unc.edu/home-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 09:35:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uprooted.unc.edu/home-about/</guid>
      <description>Why Medellín? Medellín is the second largest city in Colombia and one of the most popular areas for Venezuelan immigrants to re-settle. Our hope is that the stories we gathered in Colombia will shed light on Venezuelans&amp;rsquo; struggles and inspire positive change for the millions of people displaced by the humanitarian crisis in their home country.
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home Help</title>
      <link>https://uprooted.unc.edu/home-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 09:35:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uprooted.unc.edu/home-help/</guid>
      <description>How to Help  Many nonprofit organizations provide aid to Venezuelans in Venezuela and abroad. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Us</title>
      <link>https://uprooted.unc.edu/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 21:36:24 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uprooted.unc.edu/about/</guid>
      <description>Shedding light on the unheard stories of the Venezuelan crisis.
         We are a team of student videographers, photographers, reporters, designers, developers and faculty dedicated to decoding the political and economic crisis in Venezuela by telling the stories of families who have fled to Medellín, Colombia. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to get lost in the numbers and policy when covering Venezuela and its intrinsic, historic connection with Colombia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://uprooted.unc.edu/four-oh-four/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uprooted.unc.edu/four-oh-four/</guid>
      <description>Hey, you&#39;ve come to the wrong place! While you&#39;re a little lost, enjoy these behind-the-scenes photos.
 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>